Guide to the Greenberg Publisher Records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Greenberg Publisher Records,
1894-1976
Greenberg, Publisher.
ca. 49,000 items ( 94 boxes, and 462 v. in 31 record storage cartons )
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078838
History
Founded in 1924 by Jacob W. & David B. Greenberg. Sold to Chilton Book Company in 1958. Greenberg published in many fields including "how to" books, westerns, inspirational topics, health, cooking, agriculture, early gay fiction, sociology, police techniques, and theater.
Scope and Content
The surviving editorial, production, and publicity files of Greenberg: Publisher. The Greenberg: Publisher library includes 462 titles published by the firm. Also, personal papers of Jacob Walter Greenberg consisting of letters, manuscripts, photographs, clippings, printed ephemera, and memorabilia. These are biographical in nature relating to Greenberg, his family, friends, business associates, authors, politicians, and other public figures. Among the letters are one each from public figures including Robert Benchley, Bennett Cerf, Fiorello La Guardia, and Eleanor Roosevelt.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 6 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence and Documents
Series II: 1979 Gift
Series III: Uncatalogued. correspondence and documents re: Chilton takeover
Series IV: Uncataloged Files
Series V: Greenberg Family Personal Papers
Series VI: Oversized Material
Series VII: 1995 Gift
Subjects
Greenberg family.; Greenberg, Jacob Walter.; Greenberg, David B.; Benchley, Robert, 1889-1945.; Cerf, Bennett, 1898-1971.; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Publishers and publishing.; Cookery.; Health.; Agriculture.; Theater.; Gays--Fiction.; Police.; Sociology.; Photoprints.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence and Documents are located on-site.
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 1-95, Series V: Boxes 1-4, and the 462 volumes in 31 records storage cartons. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1979 M-79 Greenberg, Dorothy Gift
1995 Greenberg, Dorothy Gift
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence and Documents
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce
  - Anderson, Eleanor C. (Mrs. Sherwood)
  - Austin, Anne
  - Beebe, Lucius Morris
  - Bentley, Eric Russell
  - Björkman, Edwin August
  - Bromfield, Louis Brucker
  - Buckley, William Frank, Jr.
  - Burke, Kenneth Duva
  - Burnett, Whit
  - Crist, Judith Klein
  - Crosby, Percy Leo
  - Davies, Joseph Edward
  - Dietz, Howard
  - Dreiser, Theodore
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1888-
  - Gifford., James Noble
  - Goldberg, Rube
  - Green, Paul Eliot
  - Grosz, George
  - Harris, Julie
  - Hazlitt, Henry
  - Heine, Thomas Theodor
  - Horney, Karen Danielson
  - Huebsch, Ben W.
  - Inge, William
  - Isherwood, Christopher
  - Johnston, Eric A.
  - Jones, Ernest
  - Kinsey, Alfred Charles
  - Kreymborg, Alfred
  - Leach, Henry Goddard
  - Lee, Manfred B.
  - Lenroot, Katharine Fredrica
  - Levine, Isaac Don
  - Louis, Joe
  - Loveman, P
  - MacLeish, Archibald
  - Maltz, Albert
  - Menken, Helen
  - Menninger, Karl Augustus
  - Miller, Arthur
  - Montagu, Ashley
  - Muste, Arbaham John
  - Pain, Barry Eric Odell
  - Peattie, Donald Culross
  - Pegler, Westbrook
  - Prezzolini, Giuseppe
  - Rosten, Norman
  - Sarg, Tony
  - Saroyan, William
  - Schneider, Isidor
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln
  - Starrett, Vincent
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren
  - Taylor, Deems
  - Vanderbilt, Amy
  - Villa, Jose Garcia
  - Wallach, Eli
  - Wilde, Percival
  - Winslow, Thyra Samter
  - Young, Chic
- Series II: 1979 Gift
  - Baker, Newton D.
  - Benchley, Robert C.
  - Berlin, Irving
  - Carnegie, Dale
  - Cerf, Bennett A.
  - Chandler, Walter M.
  - du Pont, Pierre S.
  - Green, William
  - Greenberg, Jacob
  - Lorimer, George Horace
  - Johnson, Hugh S.
  - LaGuardia, Fiorello
  - Genthe, Arnold
  - Macfadden, Bernarr
  - Norris, Kathleen
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor
  - Smith, Alfred Emmanuel
  - Thomas, Lowell
  - Van Doren, Carl
  - Villard, Oswald Garrison
  - Woollcott, Alexander
- Series III: Uncatalogued. correspondence and documents re: Chilton takeover
  - Chilton Company (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re Chilton takeover (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re copyright assignments (Box 1)
  - Memo on Greenberg titles (Box 1)
  - Evaluation of copyrights (Box 1)
  - "In consideration for the sum of..." (Box 1)
  - Multiple Canadian copyright transfer (Box 1)
  - Printed material re Chilton takeover (Box 1)
  - Publishing properties 1 January 1958 (Box 1)
  - Required inventory to be delivered to purchace. (Box 1)
  - "Out of print titles..." (Box 1)
  - Supplemental agreement between Greenberg and Chi1ton (Box 1)
  - Titles in foreign editions (Box 1)
  - U.S. Multiple copy (Box 1)
- Series IV: Uncataloged Files
  - Adams, John Quincy (Box 2)
  - Adams, Karen (Box 2)
  - Adamson, Hans Christian (Box 2)
  - Adamson, Hans Christian & Helen Lyon Adamson (Box 3)
  - Adler, Alfred (Box 3)
  - Albaugh, William A., III & Richard D. Steuart (Box 3)
  - Alfred, Pearl & Thatcher (Box 4)
  - Amber, John T. (Box 4)
  - American Publishing Company (Box 4)
  - Anberm System Lab (Box 4)
  - Anderson, Carl (Box 4)
  - Andreyev, Leonid (Box 4)
  - Anon.: The philosophy of insanity (Box 4)
  - Anthony, Anne J. (Box 4)
  - Arstein, Helen & Carlton Moss (Box 5)
  - Atkinson, Margaret F. (Box 5)
  - Austin, Anne (Box 5)
  - "Austin, Cliff", Claude U. Rister (Box 5)
  - Ayraar, Brandt & Harford. Powel (Box 5)
  - Aymar, Brandt, ed. (Box 6)
  - Babcock, Havilah (Box 6)
  - Babington, S.E. (Box 7)
  - Bard, Andreas (Box 7)
  - "Barr, Cecil", Jack Kahana, 1887-1939 (Box 7)
  - "Barr, James", James W. Fugate (Box 7)
  - Basloe, Frank J. (Box 8)
  - "Bassett, John Keith", Lawrence A. Keating (Box 8)
  - Bates, Harry "Anthony Gilmore" (Box 8)
  - Batten, H.A. et al. (Box 8)
  - Battle,Brendan P. & Paul B. Weston (Box 8)
  - Bauer, W.W. & Florence Marvyne Bauer (Box 8)
  - Bausor, S.C. & Carlton C. Curtis (Box 9)
  - Bechdolt, Jack et al. (Box 9)
  - Bee, Claire F. (Box 9)
  - Benadum, Clarence E. (Box 9)
  - Bendrodt, James Charles (Box 9)
  - Benson, Elizabeth (Box 10)
  - "Bernard, William", Bernard Williams (Box 10)
  - Bernstein, Allen M. (Box 10)
  - Berry, Raymond A. (Box 10)
  - Biegeleisen, J.I. (Box 10)
  - Blackwood, Easley (Box 10)
  - Bush, James (Box 10)
  - Bluin, Daniel (Box 11-19)
  - Blythe, Walter Edward & Joseph Nathan Kane (Box 20)
  - Bond, Frederick Drew (Box 20)
  - Boone, Ilsey (Box 20)
  - Bookwalter Company (Box 20)
  - Bowden, Robert Douglas (Box 20)
  - Boyer, Richard O. (Box 20)
  - Braley, Berton (Box 20)
  - Bramson, Karen (Box 20)
  - Branch, Mary Lydia Bolles (Box 20)
  - Brandes, Georg (Box 20)
  - Brandt, Mary (Box 20)
  - Brennecke, Ernest F. (Box 20)
  - "Brenning, L.H.", John Hunter & William Lees (Box 20)
  - Brent, William & Milarde Brent (Box 20)
  - Brewster, Eugene V. (Box 20)
  - Brock, Lilyan (Box 21)
  - Brostrom, Ethel (Box 21)
  - Brown, Forman "Richard Meeker" (Box 21)
  - Brown, Forrest R. (Box 21)
  - Brown, Wenzell (Box 22)
  - Buck, Frederick Silas (Box 23)
  - Burbridge, Mabelle A. (Box 23)
  - Burger, Samuel (Box 23)
  - Burlingham, Margaret (Box 23)
  - Butler, Judson Rea (Box 23)
  - Caldwell, Sam (Box 23)
  - Calvert, Anna Gilbrandsen (Box 23)
  - Calvert, Bruce (Box 23)
  - Carnegie, Dale (Box 24)
  - Carroll, Jack & Edward Tarjan (Box 24)
  - Carruthers, Margaret (Box 24)
  - Carter, H. Dyson (Box 24)
  - Cartland, Barbara (Box 24)
  - Cary, William H., Jr. (Box 24)
  - Chapman, Jane A. (Box 25-26)
  - Chappell, George Shepard (Box 27)
  - Claire, Mabel (Mabel C. Bechdolt) (Box 27)
  - Clancy, Louise B., "Louise Jerrold" (Box 27)
  - Cohen, Ruth Kolko (Box 27)
  - Coleman, McAlister (Box 27)
  - Collins, Kenneth (Box 27)
  - Colt, C.C. & N.S. Keith (Box 27)
  - Conley, Austin (Box 27)
  - Conway, Charlotte (Box 27)
  - Cooper, Lawrence & Miles Leslie (Box 27)
  - Corbett, Leonora M. (Box 27)
  - "Cory, Donald Webster", Edward Sagarin (Box 27)
  - "Cory, Donald Webster", Edward Sagarin (Box 28)
  - Corwin Publishing Company (Box 28)
  - Cott, Ted. (Box 29)
  - Cragg, Alliston (Box 29)
  - Creighton, Bessy E. (Box 29)
  - Crosby, Percy Leo (Box 29)
  - Crossen, Kendall Foster (Box 29)
  - Cutler, B.D. (Box 29)
  - Cutler, John Henry (Box 29)
  - Dahl, Evelyn (Box 29)
  - Danenberg, Elsie N. (Box 29)
  - Dank, Michael Canton (Box 29)
  - Dannett, Sylvia G.L. & Frank R. Rachel (Box 30)
  - Davidson, Henry A. (Box 30)
  - Davies, Blodwen (Box 30)
  - Davis, Eugene C. (Box 30)
  - "Davis, Harry", "Richard Evans", "Roberta Hill", R.E. Sebenthall (Box 31)
  - Davis, Hassoldt (Box 31)
  - DeGarmo, Louis (Box 31)
  - De Gouy, Louis Pullig (Box 32)
  - "De Lange, Anneke", Esther H. Chase (Box 32)
  - Des Cars, Guy Augustin Marie Jean de Perusse (Box 32)
  - Deutsch, Babette (Box 32)
  - Diamond, Joseph S. (Box 32)
  - "Dick, Cappy", Robert Cleveland (Box 33)
  - Di Maggio, Joe (Box 33)
  - Drake, H.B. (Box 33)
  - "Drakeford, Tom", Thomas Grant Springer & Louis Drakeford (Box 33)
  - Dreikurs, Rudolf (Box 33)
  - Drew, Frederic (Box 33)
  - Drimmer, Frederick (Box 33)
  - Dryer, Sherman H. (Box 33)
  - Dunlap, Orrin E., Jr. (Box 34)
  - Dunton, Sam (Box 34)
  - Eager, George T. (Box 34)
  - Early, Bonnie et al. (Box 35)
  - Eastman, Max (Box 35)
  - Echols, Lee E. (Box 35)
  - Eckenrode, Hamilton James & Pocahontas Wight Edmunds (Box 35)
  - Eggleston, DeWitt Carl (Box 35)
  - Ellis, Albert (Box 35)
  - Emerson, Elliot (Box 36)
  - Enright, Walter J. (Box 36)
  - Epstein, Alvin (Box 36)
  - Essipov, Marie Armstrong (Box 36)
  - Eunson, Robert (Box 36)
  - Fabriclus, Johan (Box 37)
  - Feng, Doreen Yenhung (Box 37)
  - Field, Rudolph (Box 37)
  - Finch Robert (Box 37)
  - Firuski, Maurice (Box 38)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 38)
  - Fishermen's Press (Box 38)
  - Fitzgerald, Maurice A. & Paul B. Weston (Box 38)
  - Fletcher, Helen Jill & Jack Deckter (Box 38)
  - Florea, J.R. (Box 38)
  - "Ford, Jean", James Noble Gifford (Box 38)
  - Foster, Robert Frederick (Box 38)
  - Fox, Barry (Box 38)
  - Frank, Bert (Box 39)
  - Frank, Henry (Box 39)
  - Freeman, Kelsey (Box 39)
  - Furst, Bruno (Box 39)
  - Frommer, Arthur B. (Box 39)
  - Fugate, James (Box 39)
  - Gaillard, Paul (Box 39)
  - Galkin, Bernard (Box 39)
  - Garfunkel, Louis X. (Box 40)
  - Gauntier, Gene (Box 40)
  - Genthe, Arnold (Box 40)
  - Gibson, H.W. (Box 40)
  - Gifford, James Noble (Box 40)
  - Goode, Kenneth N. (Box 40)
  - Goodman, Derick (Box 40)
  - Gordon, Jan (Box 41)
  - Gottschalk, Louis R. (Box 41)
  - Gourmont, Remy de (Box 41)
  - Grancsay, Stephen V. (Box 41)
  - Grant, Charles Rampson (Box 41)
  - Gray, Madeline & Vass de lo Padua (Box 41)
  - Greenberg, David B. (Box 41)
  - Greenberg, David B. & Henry Schindall (Box 41)
  - Greenberg, David B. & Charles Corbin (Box 42)
  - Gregory, Norrell (Box 42)
  - Gribble, Leonard Reginald (Box 42)
  - Gropper, Milton Herbert (Box 42)
  - Groves, Ernest R. (Box 42)
  - Groves, Gladys H. & Robert A. Ross (Box 42)
  - Guggenheimer, Samuel H. (Box 42)
  - Haley, Glen (Box 42)
  - Hardy, Kay (Box 42)
  - Harian Publications (Box 42)
  - Harriman, Grace Carley (Mrs Oliver) & Helen Worden (Box 42)
  - Havighorst, C.R. (Box 42)
  - Hayes, Milton (Box 42)
  - Haywood, Charles (Box 43)
  - Heine, Thomas Theodor (Box 43)
  - Henderson, George C. (Box 43)
  - Henle, Guy (Box 43)
  - Hershfield, Harry (Box 44)
  - "Hill, King", Frank C. Robertson (Box 44)
  - Hillyer, Elinor (Box 44)
  - Hines, Jackson C. & George Vedder Jones (Box 44)
  - Hirsch, Edwin W. (Box 45)
  - Hoffmeister, Adolf (Box 45)
  - Holmes, John Haynes (Box 45)
  - Jagendorf, Moritz A. (Box 45)
  - James, Ida Elaine (Box 45)
  - Jamieson, Leland (Box 45)
  - Jastrow, Joseph (Box 45)
  - Jay, Edith (Box 45)
  - Joelson, Annette (Box 45)
  - Johnson, Paul (Box 46)
  - Johnson, Victor H. (Box 46)
  - Josef, Michel A. (Box 46)
  - Jolas, Eugene (Box 46)
  - Joseph, Robert (Box 46)
  - Kahm, Harold S. (Box 47)
  - Kahn, Samuel (Box 47)
  - Kains, Maurice G. (Box 47)
  - Kalnay, Francis (Box 48)
  - Kemp, E.C. (Box 48)
  - Karr, Jean (Box 48)
  - Karsten, Karl G. (Box 48)
  - Kaunitz, Maurice M. (Box 48)
  - Keeler, O.B. (Box 48)
  - Kelley, Douglas M. (Box 48)
  - Kendrick, Bayard H. (Box 48)
  - "Kent, Nial", William Thomas (Box 49)
  - Kerkhoff, Jack (Box 49)
  - Kerkhoff, Johnston D. (Box 49)
  - Kershner, Woward Eldred (Box 49)
  - Kessler, William F. & Paul B. Weston (Box 49)
  - Korb, Arthur (Box 50)
  - Korn, Ralph H. (Box 50)
  - Kozlenko, William (1) (Box 50)
  - Kozlenko, William (2) (Box 51)
  - Krasne, Charles J. (Box 51)
  - Krause, Earl E. (Box 51)
  - Labisky, Wallace R. (Box 52)
  - Lait, Jack (Box 52)
  - Landers, Olive Richards (Box 52)
  - Landis, Charles S. (Box 52)
  - Lang, H. Jack (Box 52)
  - Latta, Estelle (Box 52)
  - Lawton, Shailer Upton & Jules Archer (Box 52)
  - Lefèvre, Félicité (Box 52)
  - Legner, Louis E. (Box 52)
  - Lenglen, Suzanne (Box 52)
  - Lenney, John Joseph (Box 53)
  - Lenz, Sidney S. (Box 53)
  - Leonard, Laure Kittner & Ruth Walker Crosby (Box 53)
  - Leslie, Anita (Box 53)
  - Lesser, Milton (Box 53)
  - Leterman, Elmer G. (Box 53)
  - "Lewis, Dana", Raymond L. Levy (Box 53)
  - Leyson, Burr W. (Box 54)
  - Liedl, Charles (Box 54)
  - Lippman, Caro W. & Margaret (Box 54)
  - Liss, Joseph (Box 54)
  - Lockridge, Frances (Box 55)
  - "Lomax, Bliss", Harry S. Drago (Box 55)
  - Long, Julia M. (Box 55)
  - Longgood, William F. (Box 55)
  - Luban, Milton (Box 56)
  - Lustig, Leroy F. (Box 56)
  - Lyall, Archibald (Box 56)
  - "Lynn Carol", Lillian Edbrooke Montgomery (Box 56)
  - McCloskey, Richard G. (Box 56)
  - McDaniel, William R. & Harold Seligman (Box 57)
  - MacDonald, John Dann (Box 58)
  - McGraw, Jim (Box 58)
  - McNutt, William Slavens (Box 58)
  - Machamer, Jefferson (Box 58)
  - McSherry, John & Bernard Metal (Box 58)
  - Macy, R.H. Company (Box 58)
  - Madalena, Lawrence (Box 58)
  - Malvern, Gladys (Box 58)
  - Mann, Claire (Box 59)
  - Mann, Edward Beverly (Box 59)
  - Marie, Queen of Rumania (Box 59)
  - Marks, Jeannette (Box 59)
  - Marshall, Robert Chester & Mary Blair Marshall (Box 59)
  - Martin, Charles M. (Box 60)
  - Martin, Frederica (Box 60)
  - Martin, Henriette & Gita Lewis (Box 60)
  - Martone, John (Box 60)
  - "Masters, Robert V.", David A. Boehm (Box 61)
  - Mayorga, Margaret (Box 61)
  - Meek, Marcellus W. (Box 61)
  - Merlin Press (Box 61)
  - Meyer, Jerome S. (Box 62)
  - Meyer, Joseph (Box 62)
  - Meyer, Robert, Jr. (Box 62)
  - Miali, Agnes (Box 62)
  - Mikan, George Lawrence & Bill Carlson (Box 63)
  - Mille, Pierre (Box 63)
  - Miller, Anne Archbold (Box 63)
  - Montgomery, James Stuart (Box 63)
  - Moore, Samuel Taylor & Leo M. Solomon (Box 63)
  - Morton, Guy E. (Box 64)
  - Morton, Katherine G. & E.E. Morton (Box 64)
  - Munkacsi, Martin (Box 64)
  - Murphy, Margot "Jane Holt" (Box 64)
  - Murphy, Paul A. (Box 64)
  - Myers, Garry Cleveland (Box 64)
  - Nelson, Raymond E. (Box 64)
  - Newcomb, William W (Box 64)
  - Newman, Joseph Simon (Box 64)
  - Nipponnoodies. (Box 65)
  - Nygaard, Norman E (Box 65)
  - Oakley, W.W. (Box 65)
  - O'Brian, George A. (Box 65)
  - O 'Hara, Jack & Eddie Arcaro (Box 66)
  - O'Neal, George S. (Box 66)
  - Ormond, Leon (Box 66)
  - Ormston, Frank D. (Box 66)
  - Ornstein, Jacob A. (Box 66)
  - O'Shae, Michael V. (Box 66)
  - Owen, Frank "Roswell Williams" (Box 67)
  - Owen, Jean Z. (Box 67)
  - Pape, Richard (Box 67)
  - Paradis, Adrian A. (Box 67)
  - Parmelee, Claude E. (Box 67)
  - Pasbko, Stanley & Pearl (Box 68-69)
  - Penny, Edythe (Box 69)
  - Pinkham, Spencer (Box 69)
  - Pirie, Antoinette (Box 69)
  - Pitigrilli, M. (Box 69)
  - Platt, Samuel C. "Sam See" (Box 69)
  - Poling, Daniel A. (Box 70)
  - Polowe, David (Box 71)
  - Posnack, Emanuel R. (Box 71)
  - Powel, Harford (Box 71)
  - Poynter, Beulah (Box 71)
  - Prager, Natalie Purvin (Box 71)
  - Pragnell, Festus W. (Box 71)
  - Pratt, Caroline & Jessie Stanton (Box 71)
  - Price, Edith (Box 71)
  - Price, Matlack & A. Thornton Bishop (Box 71)
  - Prideaux, Tom (Box 72)
  - Prince, Walter N. (Box 72)
  - Prior, William E. (Box 73)
  - Publicaciones Atlas (Box 73)
  - Quin, B.G. (Box 73)
  - Radke, Ernest F. (Box 73)
  - Radl, Lucia (Box 73)
  - Rabbino, Edna (Box 73)
  - Randall, William R. (Box 74)
  - Rappard, William Emmanuel (Box 74)
  - Ravel, Judith (Box 74)
  - Reynolds, H. Atwood (Box 74)
  - Reynolds, Milton (Box 74)
  - Richards, R.R. (Box 74)
  - Richardson, Chalmer 0. (Box 74)
  - Richardson, Ethel Park (Box 74)
  - Riggins, Dean (Box 75)
  - Riling, Ray (Box 75)
  - Roberts, Carl Eric Bechhofer (Box 75)
  - Roberts, Elizabeth R. (Box 75)
  - Robinson, Jackie (Box 75)
  - Rodney, George Brydges (Box 75)
  - Rose, Helen (Box 75)
  - Rosenthal, George S. (Box 76)
  - Rosenthal, Harold (Box 76)
  - Rothenberg, Alan Baer (Box 76)
  - Rothenberg, Charles (Box 76)
  - Rothman, Michael (Box 76)
  - Royer, Louis-Charles (Box 76)
  - Rukeyser, Merryle Stanley (Box 76)
  - Rundell, Wyatt R. (Box 76)
  - Rutzebeck, Hjalmar (Box 76)
  - Salmon, Richard D. (Box 77)
  - Salomon, Irving (Box 77)
  - Samworth, Thomas G. (Box 78)
  - Sangster, Margaret Elizabeth (Box 78)
  - Santillan, D.A. de (Box 78)
  - Sarg, Tony (Box 78)
  - Santini, Piero (Box 78)
  - Scherz, Alfred (Box 79)
  - Schick, Bela & William Rosenson (Box 79)
  - Schillinger, Joseph (Box 79)
  - Schneider, Edouard (Box 79)
  - Schoenberner, EleonoreNcrac, "Ellen Caren" (Box 79)
  - Schoor, Gene (Box 79)
  - Scott, Adrian (Box 79)
  - Scott, George, Ryley (Box 80)
  - Scott, Neil (Box 80)
  - Scott, Temple (Box 80)
  - Scully, Frank (Box 80)
  - Seadler, Albert B & Miriam R, Wachtel (Box 80)
  - Seldes, George (Box 80)
  - Selling, Lowell S. (Box 80)
  - Sharpe, Ruth Collier (Box 80)
  - Shepard, Michael (Box 80)
  - Sheridan, Clare (Box 80)
  - Sherrill, Dorothy (Box 80)
  - Shipley, Joseph T. (Box 80)
  - Simon Maron J. (Box 81)
  - Simonhoff, Harry (Box 81)
  - Smedley, Doree & Lura Robinson (Box 81)
  - Smertenko, Johan J. (Box 81)
  - Smith, Betty (Box 81)
  - Smith, Charles Zachariah (Box 82)
  - Smith, Ken (Box 82)
  - Snyder, Harry M. (Box 82)
  - Snyder, Louis L. (Box 83)
  - Sobel, Helen (Box 83)
  - Sparling, E. Earl (Box 83)
  - Sper, Norman (Box 83)
  - Springer, Thomas Grant (Box 83)
  - Steelman, L.W. (Box 84)
  - Steiner, Lee R. (Box 84)
  - Sterling, Forest J. (Box 84)
  - Stevens, Edmund (Box 84)
  - Stevenson, Elmo N. (Box 84)
  - Stieri, Emanuele (Box 84)
  - Stiles, Villa & B.D. Cutler (Box 84)
  - Stott, Leila (Box 84)
  - Stuart, Lyle (Box 85)
  - Studer, Paul (Box 85)
  - Sturgeon, Theodore (Box 85)
  - Sutphen, P.L. (Box 85)
  - Sutton, Marvin (Box 85)
  - Swan, Alexander, 2nd (Box 85)
  - Symons, Arthur (Box 85)
  - Syms (Box 85)
  - Taylor, Demetria M. (Box 86)
  - Taylor, Jeanne H. (Box 86)
  - Taylor, Norman (Box 86)
  - Taylor, Samuel W. (Box 86)
  - Tellier, André (Box 87)
  - Thomas, William (Box 87)
  - Thompson, Jim (Box 87)
  - Thornton, June (Box 87)
  - Thornton, Willis (Box 87)
  - "Thorn, Ronald Scott", Ronald Wilkinson (Box 87)
  - Thurber, Helen H. (Box 88)
  - Torson, Gladys (Box 88)
  - Trego, Frank H. (Box 88)
  - Tully, Jim (Box 88)
  - Turpin, Lawry (Box 88)
  - Turrell, George B. (Box 88)
  - United Features Syndicate: Ferd'nand by Mik (Box 88)
  - van Vogt, Alfred E. (Box 88)
  - Veith, Ilza and Leo Zimmerman (Box 88)
  - Vithaldas, Yogi (Box 88)
  - Vocational Guidance Research (Box 88)
  - von Hagen, Victor Wolfgang (Box 89)
  - "Wahi, Loren", Lawrence Mad.alena (Box 89)
  - Wahl, Paul F. (Box 89)
  - Wallack, L. Robert (Box 90)
  - Walton, Luke (Box 90)
  - Warner, William Henry (Box 90)
  - Warren, Lillian (Box 90)
  - Warshow, Robert Irving (Box 90)
  - Weber, Max (Box 90)
  - Weil, Ann (Box 90)
  - Weller, Charles F. (Box 90)
  - Werry, Richard R. (Box 90)
  - "West, Ward", Hal Borland (Box 90)
  - Weston, Paul B. & Frederick W. Egan (Box 91)
  - Widdemer, Margaret (Box 91)
  - Wiechert, Ernst Emil (Box 91)
  - Wile, Ira S. (Box 91)
  - Wilde, Percival (Box 91)
  - Wilkinson, Charlotte W. (Box 92)
  - Williams. Idabel (Box 92)
  - Willism, George (Box 92)
  - Winant, Lewis (Box 92)
  - Winterich, John T. (Box 93)
  - Wohlberg, Meg (Box 93)
  - Wolf, Morris Herbert (Box 93)
  - Wolf, Robert A. & Paul Wick (Box 93)
  - Wolfe, Don M. (Box 94)
  - Wood, Clement (Box 94)
  - Worden, Helen (Box 94)
  - Worth, Helen (Box 94)
  - Youmans, C.L. & Morgan Shepard "John Martin" (Box 94)
  - Zaidenburg, Arthur (Box 94)
  - Zistel, Era (Box 94)
  - Zola, Emile (Box 94)
- Series V: Greenberg Family Personal Papers
  - Marks Family Genealogy (Box 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Documents (Box 1)
  - Itineraries (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts (Box 1)
  - Printed Ephemera, 1894-1976 (Box 2)
  - Catalogued Photographs A-Z (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 1895-1939 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 1940-1970 (Box 4)
  - Oversized Photographs, 1938-1952 (Box 4)
  - Colored Drawing and Photograph (World War I) (Box 4)
- Series VI: Oversized Material
  - "Inez and Jimmy in Japan" photograph, Japan, 1966
  - Birthday Greeting to JWG colored drawing, 5 January l954
  - Si Seadler printed ephemera (various dates)
  - Birthday greeting to JWG, 5 January 1969
- Series VII: 1995 Gift
  - Greenberg Publisher Records
    - Author's Photographs Greenberg Publishers, 1920s-1950s (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Author's Photographs Greenberg Publishers, 1920s-1950s (Box Flat Box 730)
    - Crown Publishers (Nat Wartels), 1953, 1958 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Kerkhoff, Jack, 1952-1953 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Scully, Frank, 1961 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Thornton, Willis (June), 1957 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Greenberg Personal Family Papers
    - Correspondence
      - Greenberg, Dorothy to Jacob, 1941-1949 (Box 95, Folder 6)
      - Greenberg, Jacob to Dorothy, 1941-1964, Undated, (4 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 7 to 10)
      - Greenberg, Jacob to Children, 1961 (Box 95, Folder 11)
      - Greenberg, Fay, 1938 (Box 95, Folder 12)
      - Greenberg, Garry, 1954-1957 (Box 95, Folder 13)
      - Steinhart, Lee, 1960 (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Diary (Jacob Greenberg), 1952 (Box 95, Folder 15)
      (On his marriage problems)
    - Judgment in Divorce Proceedings, 1940 (Box 95, Folder 16)